<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction to Linguistics on linguistics</title>
    <link>https://emtomo.github.io/linguistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction to Linguistics on linguistics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://emtomo.github.io/linguistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://emtomo.github.io/linguistics/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emtomo.github.io/linguistics/about/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Linguistics This website is designed to give you an introduction to the field of Linguistics. It contains introductory lessons on a variety of Linguistic topics to give you an overview of the subject and hopefully inspire further interest. The purpose of this website is to make Linguistics accessible and highlight the advantages of studying linguistics to people who may not have heard of this subject before.
What is Linguistics?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphology</title>
      <link>https://emtomo.github.io/linguistics/posts/morphology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emtomo.github.io/linguistics/posts/morphology/</guid>
      <description>What is mophology? Morphology is the study of the form and structure of words.
Morphemes The smallest unit of language that has meaning is a morpheme. If you try to think of an example of units of language which cannot be broken into smaller parts you discover that here are different types of morphemes - those that are words in their own right (eg. book), and those that are not (eg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonetics</title>
      <link>https://emtomo.github.io/linguistics/posts/phonetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emtomo.github.io/linguistics/posts/phonetics/</guid>
      <description>What is Phonetics? Phonetics is the study of human speech.
How do humans speak? To speak, air from the lungs travels to the larynx where the air either vibrates the vocal folds or is allowed to pass through. Articulators in the mouth and nose shape the airflow to make speech sounds.
How are different sounds produced? To produce different sounds, we change the shape of articulators in the mouth and nose including the tongue, lips and teeth, the alveolar ridge, the palate, the velum, and the nasal cavity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantics</title>
      <link>https://emtomo.github.io/linguistics/posts/semantics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emtomo.github.io/linguistics/posts/semantics/</guid>
      <description>What is semantics? Semantics is the study of meaning in language.
What is meaning? This is a hard concept to define and is a question that philosophers have been debating for centuries. For Linguistis, when understanding the meaning of an utterance, the meaning is determined by the meaning of its parts and the way they are put together - this is called the Principle of Compositionality.
There is a difference between the literal sentence meaning and the communicated meaning of a sentence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sociolinguistics</title>
      <link>https://emtomo.github.io/linguistics/posts/sociolinguistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emtomo.github.io/linguistics/posts/sociolinguistics/</guid>
      <description>What is sociolinguistics? Sociolinguistics is the study of language and society. Sociolinguists are concerned with the use of different linguistic variants in particular linguistic and social contexts.
Linguistic Variables A linguistic variable is a set of alternative ways that something can be said. These different ways of saying the same thing are called variants. There are different types of variation:
 Syntactic (sentence structure)/grammatical E.g. He won’t go / He’ll not go Lexis - words</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax</title>
      <link>https://emtomo.github.io/linguistics/posts/syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emtomo.github.io/linguistics/posts/syntax/</guid>
      <description>What is syntax? Syntax is the study of the structure of language.
Constituency Sentences are made up of sub-groups of words. These are called constituents - a string of words in a sentence that speakers can manipulate as a single chunk. We have tests we can use to see if a string of words is a constituent. Note that one negative test does not mean the string is not a constituent.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>